Guide to the New York Times Company records. Arthur Hays Sulzberger papers
New York Public Library
- Series I. People, 1873, 1884-1968, 1972, 1975, n.d; 86.25 boxes, 1 volume
  - Peabody, Margaret, 1958 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Peabody, Mary, 1964 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Peabody, Maude, 1966 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Pearlson, Eleanor D., 1953-1955 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Pearson, Drew, 1926, 1933, 1941, 1950 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Peary, Robert Edwin
  - Peck, David W., 1956-1958 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Peck, Seymour
  - Pecora, Ferdinand, 1958 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Pegler, Westbrook, 1952-1962 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Pegram, George B., 1958 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Peixotto, Daniel L. M.
  - Pelenyi, John, 1951, 1955, 1967 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Pelz, Edward J., 1953-1967 (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Pelz, Walter and Edith, 1939-1947 (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - Pemberton, Brock, 1949 (Box 57, Folder 15)
  - Penney, James Cash, 1954-1955 (Box 57, Folder 16)
  - Percy, Charles H., 1959 (Box 57, Folder 17)
  - Perilman, Nathan A.
  - Perkins, Frances T.
  - Perlman, Alfred E., 1959, 1962 (Box 57, Folder 18)
  - Peron, Juan D.
  - Perrin, Dana H.
  - Perry, Stuart and Maude Perry, 1942-1952 (Box 57, Folder 19)
  - Pershing, John J., 1930-1934 (Box 57, Folder 20)
  - Peters, C. Brooks, 1941, 1948-1950 (Box 57, Folder 21)
  - Pflaum, Irving, 1950 (Box 57, Folder 22)
  - Phalen, Clifton W., 1961 (Box 57, Folder 23)
  - Philip, Percy J., 1935-1956 (Box 57, Folder 24-25)
  - Philippe, C. C., 1962, 1967 (Box 57, Folder 26)
  - Phillips, Paul J. (Mrs.), 1961 (Box 57, Folder 27)
  - Phillips, Ruby Hart, 1935-1963 (Box 57, Folder 28)
  - Pickett, Clarence E.
  - Pierce, Bert, 1947-1958 (Box 57, Folder 29)
  - Pierson, Joseph
  - Pike, H. Harvey and Constance Pike, 1953-1968 (Box 57, Folder 30)
  - Pinkley, Virgil
  - Pius XII, Pope, 1957 (Box 57, Folder 31)
  - Plaza Lasso, Galo
  - Plumb, Robert K., 1957, 1962 (Box 57, Folder 32)
  - Podell, Jacob J., 1953-1955 (Box 57, Folder 33)
  - Polansky, Phyllis Leilani, 1960-1967 (Box 57, Folder 34)
  - Poliakoff, Vladimir, 1937-1939 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    Includes correspondence about Poliakoff's articles on foreign affairs, under the pen name Augur, some of which were published in the NYT.
  - Poling, Daniel A., II, 1959-1961 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Pomfret, John D., 1966-1967 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Pool, David de Sola and Tamar de Sola Pool, 1944-1957 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Pool, Ruth, 1956-1961 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Poore, Charles, 1941-1960 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Pope, Generoso, Jr.
  - Pope, James S.
  - Pope, Loren, 1958 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Pope, Virginia, 1949-1959 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Popham, John N., 1952-1961 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Porter, Brayton A., Jr., 1957 (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Porter, Cole, 1962 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Porter, Russell B., 1929-1962 (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Post, Langdon, 1952-1953, 1964 (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Post, Robert P., 1941-1945 (Box 58, Folder 14)
  - Post, Wiley
  - Postal, Bernard, 1925-1926, 1951, 1954 (Box 58, Folder 15)
  - Postley, Howard A., 1954-1959 (Box 58, Folder 16)
  - Potter, Charles Francis, 1933-1941 (Box 58, Folder 17)
  - Poulett, Bridgett
  - Powell, Adam Clayton, Jr.
  - Powell, Francis T., 1936-1941 (Box 58, Folder 18)
  - Powell, Richard R.
  - Pralle, Ilse, 1947-1949 (Box 58, Folder 19)
  - Pratt, Fletcher
  - Prentis, Edmund Astley, 1953-1954 (Box 58, Folder 20)
  - Prescott, Orville, 1954-1955, 1966 (Box 58, Folder 21)
  - Pressman, Barney, 1965 (Box 58, Folder 22)
  - Pressman, Gabriel, 1949 (Box 58, Folder 23)
  - Prettyman, Virgil, 1952 (Box 58, Folder 24)
  - Price, Robert, 1965 (Box 58, Folder 25)
  - Prochazka, George A., Jr., 1966 (Box 58, Folder 26)
  - Procope, Hjalmar J., 1940-1948 (Box 58, Folder 27)
  - Proffitt, Charles G., 1956, 1965-1966 (Box 58, Folder 28)
  - Proffitt, Henry W., 1959 (Box 58, Folder 29)
  - Profumo, Jack, 1952 (Box 58, Folder 30)
  - Proskauer, Joseph M., 1944-1959 (Box 58, Folder 31)
  - Puckette, Charles McDonald and Elizabeth Puckette, 1948-1962 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Pulbrook, Susan, Lady and Sir Eustace Pulbrook, 1949-1968 (Box 59, Folder 2-5)
  - Pulitzer, Herbert
  - Pulitzer, Joseph, 1944-1955 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Pulitzer, Joseph, Jr., 1955-1956 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Putnam, Albert W., 1951 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Putnam, George
  - Pyle, Ernie, 1945 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Quinn, William W., 1959 (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Rabi, Isidor I.
  - Rabinowitz, Aaron and Clara Rabinowitz, 1954-1962 (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Rabinowitz, Alan, 1953-1955 (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Rabinowitz, Louis M., 1953-1957 (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - Radcliffe, Cyril John, 1957 (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - Radford, Arthur W., 1952-1953 (Box 59, Folder 15)
  - Radziwill, Stanislas and Lee Bouvier Radziwill, 1961 (Box 59, Folder 16)
  - Rae, Bruce, 1944-1962 (Box 59, Folder 17)
  - Raffel, Louis, 1943-1944 (Box 59, Folder 18)
  - Ragona, Andrew L., 1948-1968 (Box 59, Folder 19)
  - Raick, Marie-Claire Simon and Julien O. Raick
    - 1952-1968 (Box 59, Folder 20-22)
    - 1921, 1932-1951 (Box 60, Folder 1-8)
  - Railey, Hilton H., 1930-1959 (Box 60, Folder 9-11)
    Hilton Railey's first contact with AHS was in his role as public relations manager for Admiral Byrd's Antarctic expedition. Subsequently, he was involved in several other expeditions that The Times covered or contracted to cover. At the start of the Second World War, he joined The Times staff as an assistant to Hanson Baldwin (1941), and, on special assignment from AHS, conducted a survey of Army morale, which resulted in the "Railey Report" to the President and Secretary of War and was a major factor in the establishment of the information and education program in the U.S. military services.Papers concerning these activities are in the appropriate subject folders as indicated in the cross-references following. The papers in these two folders are mostly personal correspondence between Railey and AHS, including details about his employment by and severance from The Times, financial assistance given him by The Times and by AHS personally, comments about world events and U.S. policies, and Railey's books and poems (the latter published under the pen name Peter Cameron). Photo (1930).Hilton Railey's first contact with AHS was in his role as public relations manager for Admiral Byrd's Antarctic expedition. Subsequently, he was involved in several other expeditions that The Times covered or contracted to cover. At the start of the Second World War, he joined The Times staff as an assistant to Hanson Baldwin (1941), and, on special assignment from AHS, conducted a survey of Army morale, which resulted in the "Railey Report" to the President and Secretary of War and was a major factor in the establishment of the information and education program in the U.S. military services.Papers concerning these activities are in the appropriate subject folders as indicated in the cross-references following. The papers in these two folders are mostly personal correspondence between Railey and AHS, including details about his employment by and severance from The Times, financial assistance given him by The Times and by AHS personally, comments about world events and U.S. policies, and Railey's books and poems (the latter published under the pen name Peter Cameron). Photo (1930).
  - Rains, Isaac, 1935-1936 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Ramey, George E., 1946-1958 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Ramsay, Archibald Henry Maule, 1941 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Randall, Clarence B., 1954-1962 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Randau, Clem J., 1948 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Randolph, Woodruff
  - Rankin, William H., 1947-1951 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Rao, Binod U., 1953 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Raoul, Kit, 1962 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Rappleye, Willard C., 1958, 1961 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Raskin, Abraham H., 1945-1967 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Rasponi, Caroline and Lanfranco Rasponi, 1941-1942, 1964 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Ray, E. Lansing, 1946-1955 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Ray, Grace E., 1956-1968 (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Rayher, Edward R., 1953-1957 (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Raymond, Henry Jarvis, 1936-1937 (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - Raymond, Jack, 1946-1967 (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - Raymont, Henry, 1963 (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - Read, Samuel R.
  - Read, Thomas and Avis Read, 1967 (Box 61, Folder 18)
  - Reading, Stelle, 1942-1943 (Box 61, Folder 19)
  - Reay-Mackey, Moira, 1956-1964 (Box 61, Folder 20)
  - Redmond, Roland L., 1959 (Box 61, Folder 21)
  - Redpath, Albert G., 1953 (Box 61, Folder 22)
  - Reece, Carroll M.
  - Reed, Henry Hope, 1957, 1966 (Box 61, Folder 23)
  - Reed, Joseph Verner, 1953-1967 (Box 61, Folder 24)
  - Reed, Stanley, 1957 (Box 61, Folder 25)
  - Reid, Cornelius J., 1952-1957 (Box 61, Folder 26)
  - Reid, Helen Rogers, 1956-1963 (Box 61, Folder 27)
  - Reid, Ogden Mills, 1949 (Box 61, Folder 28)
  - Reid, Ogden Rogers, 1956-1958 (Box 61, Folder 29)
  - Reid, Whitelaw, 1959 (Box 61, Folder 30)
  - Reil, Lawrence Walther and Rita Matthias Reil, 1934-1946, 1953 (Box 61, Folder 31)
  - Reimer, Otto B. and Ursula Squier Reimer, 1953, 1962-1968 (Box 61, Folder 32)
  - Reiss, Vera, 1962 (Box 61, Folder 33)
  - Resor, Stanley
  - Reston, James B. and Sally Fulton Reston
    These four folders contain AHS's correspondence with Reston, and with other persons about Reston, mostly in connection with Reston's career and personal matters. Papers dealing with the general nature of Reston's column on the editorial page and his interpretive articles and news dispatches, as well as with readers' comments on diverse articles, are included here; however, papers dealing with the major subjects Reston covered in his articles and news reports are in the appropriate subject folders, most of which are listed in the cross-references following.Of special interest:--Letters and memoranda about Reston's role in the Washington Bureau, his assignments and responsibilities, and his position vis-a-vis Arthur Krock (1944, 1946-1947).--Reston's memoranda about publishing news in the light of national security considerations (August 29, 1944).--Reston's role in the London Bureau and relations with Raymond Kaniell (1943-1944).NOTE: In his letters to Reston, AHS often addresses him as "Dear PECTOH", which may be assumed to be a transliteration of "Reston" in the Cyrillic alphabet. (Reston had travelled to the Soviet Union with AHS in 1943 on a Red Cross mission). However, these papers give no clue to the origin of Reston's use of "Mr. Gus" in addressing AHS.In 1985, Reston confirmed the interpretation of PECTOH (by telephone) and explained the "Mr. Gus" in a letter included in this file.
    - 1959-1967, 1985 (Box 61, Folder 34-35)
    - 1941-1959 (Box 62, Folder 1-6)
  - Reuther, Walter P., 1945 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Revesz, Andres, 1954-1959 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Reyburn, Samuel W., 1955, 1961 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Reynolds, Quentin, 1950 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Rhee, Syngman, 1953-1955, 1965 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Rheinstein, Alfred, 1937-1968 (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - Rheinstein, Sidney, 1955-1968 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - Rheinstrom, Robert I., 1954-1955 (Box 62, Folder 14)
  - Rhind, Flora M., 1957-1962 (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - Ribicoff, Abraham, 1955, 1959 (Box 62, Folder 16)
  - Rice, Elmer, 1957 (Box 62, Folder 17)
  - Rich, Irene
  - Richards, Bernard G., 1941-1968 (Box 62, Folder 18-21)
  - Rickenbacker, Edward V., 1940-1967 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Ridder, Victor F., 1934-1963 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Ridgway, Matthew B., 1951-1953 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Rieben, Louis, 1954 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Riegelman, Harold, 1934-1938, 1955 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Ries, Henry, 1947-1951, 1955 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Rinehart, Frederick R. and Elizabeth Rinehart, 1961-1962 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Roach, James, 1952-1953, 1961 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Robbins, Leonard H., 1942-1947 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Roberts, Owen J., 1950 (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Roberts, Roy A., 1944-1967 (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Robertson, Hugh W., 1957 (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - Robertson, Nan, 1962 (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - Robertson, Walter S., 1953-1955 (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - Robinson, Bernard B., 1953-1958 (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - Robinson, Beverly, 1940 (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - Robinson, William, 1954 (Box 63, Folder 17)
  - Robinson, William S., 1945 (Box 63, Folder 18)
  - Robledo, Bridgett Poulett, 1953-1967 (Box 63, Folder 19-21)
  - Robson, Arthur D., Jr., 1944 (Box 63, Folder 22)
  - Rockefeller, David, 1953-1965 (Box 63, Folder 23)
  - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1937-1960 (Box 63, Folder 24)
  - Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, 1946-1967 (Box 63, Folder 25)
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S., 1966 (Box 63, Folder 26)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1943-1968 (Box 63, Folder 27)
  - Rodenberg, Albert (Mrs.), 1953 (Box 63, Folder 28)
  - Rodgers, Richard and Dorothy Rodgers, 1954-1968 (Box 63, Folder 29)
  - Roehm, Ernst
  - Roelofs, Richard, Jr., 1948 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Roesen, Oscar, 1956 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Rogers, Lindsay, 1956, 1961 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Rogers, Rollin L., 1952 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Rogers, Will, 1926-1930 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Rogers, William P., 1958-1961 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Rommel, Erwin, 1951-1952 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Romulo, Carlos P., 1946-1956, 1961, 1968 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Ronne, Finn
  - Roosevelt, Archibald B., 1951-1954 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Roosevelt, Belle, 1958-1959 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1940-1963 (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Roosevelt, Elliott, 1947 (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1932-1950 (Box 64, Folder 13-14)
    Includes letters, memoranda, and other documents about diverse aspects of Roosevelt's policies and actions, many concerning his attitude toward and relations with the NYT and the press in general, AHS's correspondence with Roosevelt, and his memoranda on his three meetings with the President (1936, 1937, 1939).
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., Jr., 1949, 1954 (Box 64, Folder 15)
  - Roosevelt, Nicholas, 1926-1931, 1944-1962 (Box 64, Folder 16)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, Jr. and Eleanor Roosevelt, 1940-1951 (Box 64, Folder 17)
  - Root, Dorothy M., 1931, 1941-1951, 1959 (Box 64, Folder 18)
  - Root, Elihu, Jr.
  - Root, Nancy, 1956 (Box 64, Folder 19)
  - Root, Oren, 1949 (Box 64, Folder 20)
  - Roots, John McCook, 1948-1964 (Box 64, Folder 21)
  - Roper, Elmo, 1944 (Box 64, Folder 22)
  - Rorimer, James J., 1957-1966 (Box 64, Folder 23)
  - Rose, Charles Jules, 1953-1954 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Rose, Paul W., 1954, 1957 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Rosenberg, Anna M., 1936-1956 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Rosenberg, Gustave G., 1956-1965 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Rosenberg, James N., 1935-1936, 1943-1949, 1953-1966 (Box 65, Folder 5-7)
  - Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel Rosenberg
  - Rosenberger, Carl, 1952 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Rosenbloom, Michael, 1954 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Rosengren, Roswell P., 1952-1966 (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Rosenhaupt, Hans, 1959 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Rosenheim, Rosalie, 1942-1949 (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Rosenman, Samuel I., 1941, 1959, 1968 (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - Rosenschein, Matthew, Jr., 1957-1959 (Box 296, Folder 5)
  - Rosenschein, Matthew, Jr. and Judith Sulzberger Rosenchein, 1946-1957 (Box 65, Folder 14-15)
    These folders contains AHS's correspondence with Judy and her husband, mostly about financial and other personal matters, and his correspondence with others about them. Some of his letters and poems addressed to the Rosencheins' children, James and Daniel, are included, however, the boys were later adopted by Judy's second husband, Richard N. Cohen, and most of the papers concerning them are included under Cohen, Richard N. and Judith Sulzberger Cohen.
  - Rosenstiel, Lewis S., 1950-1953, 1965 (Box 65, Folder 16)
  - Rosenthal, Abraham M., 1954-1967 (Box 65, Folder 17)
  - Rosenthal, Arthur J., Jr., 1941 (Box 65, Folder 18)
  - Rosenwald, Lessing J., 1948-1959 (Box 65, Folder 19)
  - Ross, Albion H., 1941-1958 (Box 65, Folder 20)
  - Ross, Harold W.
  - Ross, Malcolm
  - Ross, Thomas, 1959 (Box 65, Folder 21)
  - Rossant, Murray J., 1962-1967 (Box 65, Folder 22)
  - Rossbach, Max J. H. and Mabel Rossbach, 1933-1967 (Box 65, Folder 23-24)
  - Rosten, Leo C.
  - Roston, Arnold, 1960-1961 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Rothermere, Esmond, 1946-1958 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Rothman, A. D., 1941, 1947 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Rothman, Jack, 1956-1957 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Rothman, John
  - Rothschild, Melvin M., Jr. and Mary Frank Rothschild, 1962 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Rothschild, Walter N. and Carola Rothschild, 1951-1960 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Rousseau, Theodore, 1938-1945, 1952-1953 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Rozsa, Laszlo, 1952-1953 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Rubicam, Raymond, 1943 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Rubin, Max J., 1961 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Rubissow, George A., 1951 (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Ruch, Walter W., 1945-1949 (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Ruehl, Theodore C.
  - Rukeyser, Louis R., 1954 (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - Ruml, Beardsley, 1955, 1959 (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Ruprecht, Walter, 1953 (Box 66, Folder 15)
  - Rusk, Dean, 1955, 1960-1968 (Box 66, Folder 16)
  - Rusk, Howard A. and Gladys Rusk, 1945-1967 (Box 66, Folder 17-20)
    AHS met Rusk through the Red Cross. Their mutual interest in the problems of returning World War II veterans prompted AHS to offer him the opportunity to write a regular column on veterans, especially the physically handicapped. This was quickly expanded to cover the problems of the handicapped in general. These folders contain AHS's correspondence with Rusk about his column and diverse related medical matters, about Rusk's many awards and about personal matters. Rusk also had a major role in advising AHS about treatment of his various illnesses.
  - Russell, Andrew H., 1950 (Box 66, Folder 21)
  - Russell, Bertrand, 1956-1963 (Box 66, Folder 22)
  - Russell, Edward
  - Russell, Lucien T., 1929 (Box 66, Folder 23)
  - Ryan, Cornelius E., 1953-1959 (Box 66, Folder 24)
  - Ryan, Joe A., 1952 (Box 66, Folder 25)
  - Rywell, Martin and Ethel Rywell, 1957-1959 (Box 66, Folder 26)
  - Saarinen, Aline B., 1947-1961 (Box 66, Folder 27)
  - Sabine, Gordon
  - Safford, Carlton R., 1954-1966 (Box 66, Folder 28)
  - Safranek, Milos and Germaine Leroux
  - Sage, William, Jr., 1939, 1944 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Saint, Shirley Wolf, 1959-1960 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Salisbury, Harrison E., 1949-1967 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Salk, Jonas E., 1955 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Sammartino, Peter, 1957-1959 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Sammis, Walter H., 1954-1958 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Sampaio, Sebastiao, 1949-1951 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Samuels, Gertrude
  - Samuels, Howard J., 1966 (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Sand, Leonard B. and Ann Sulzberger Sand, 1956-1968 (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Sanders, Durward E., 1953 (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - Sanger, Elliott M., Jr., 1955-1957 (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Sanger, Elliott M., Sr. and Eleanor Sanger, 1951-1968 (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - Sanger, Margaret, 1956-1958 (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Sardi, Vincent, Jr., 1957-1958 (Box 67, Folder 14)
  - Sardi, Vincent, Sr., 1958 (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - Sarnoff, David, 1955-1968 (Box 67, Folder 16)
  - Satar Khan, Abdul
  - Sauerwein, Jules, 1927, 1932-1933, 1939-1941 (Box 67, Folder 17)
  - Sayre, Francis B., Jr.
  - Schaar, Emily Bernheim, 1953-1961 (Box 67, Folder 18)
  - Schaffer, Robert H., 1954-1955 (Box 67, Folder 19)
  - Scheidemann, Philipp, 1933 (Box 67, Folder 20)
  - Schiff, Dorothy, 1945, 1956, 1959 (Box 67, Folder 21)
  - Schiff, William, 1954-1964 (Box 67, Folder 22)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr., 1965 (Box 67, Folder 23)
  - Schmidt, Dana Adams, 1947-1952, 1962-1968 (Box 67, Folder 24)
  - Schmidt, J. E., 1952-1958 (Box 67, Folder 25)
  - Scholle, Helen, 1961-1965 (Box 67, Folder 26)
  - Schonberg, Harold C., 1960 (Box 67, Folder 27)
  - Schubart, Dorothy, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 28)
  - Schullinger, Rudolph N., 1956-1967 (Box 67, Folder 29)
  - Schultz, Benjamin, 1948-1951 (Box 67, Folder 30)
  - Schultz, Joseph
  - Schumach, Murray
  - Schuster, Max Lincoln, 1947-1960 (Box 67, Folder 31)
  - Schwager, Charles, 1943-1953 (Box 67, Folder 32)
  - Schwartz, Daniel, 1953-1966 (Box 67, Folder 33)
  - Schwartz, Harry, 1948-1967 (Box 67, Folder 34)
  - Schwarz, Daniel, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Schweitzer, Louis, 1959 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Scopes, John Thomas, 1956 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Scott, Laurence P.
  - Scott, Martha
  - Scripps, W. E.
  - Searle, Robert W.
  - Sedgwick, Alexander C., 1937-1961 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Segal, Philip, 1949, 1954 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Seigel, Kalman, 1957 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Seixas, Benjamin Mendez
  - Seixas, Gershom Mendes, 1929 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Seixas, Moses
  - Selassie, Haile
  - Selden, Charles A., 1933-1937, 1944, 1956 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Seldes, George, 1938-1968 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Selfridge, H. Gordon
  - Seligman, Edwin R. A., 1940-1944 (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - Seligman, Eustace, 1934-1965 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Sellew, Waldo, 1954-1968 (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - Seltzer, Louis, 1954-1956 (Box 68, Folder 13)
  - Semal, Jean P., 1948-1951 (Box 68, Folder 14)
  - Sensenbrenner, Frank J., 1939-1957 (Box 68, Folder 15)
  - Seres, Monique, 1955-1958, 1962 (Box 68, Folder 16)
  - Serkin, Rudolph, 1955-1956 (Box 68, Folder 17)
  - Sforza, Carlo, 1931-1942, 1951 (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Shafer, Jack
  - Shakespeare, William
  - Shannon, William V., 1967 (Box 68, Folder 19)
  - Shapera, Sol, 1947 (Box 68, Folder 20)
  - Shaplen, Joseph, 1935-1936 (Box 68, Folder 21)
  - Shapley, Harlow
  - Shaver, Dorothy, 1942, 1954-1959 (Box 68, Folder 22)
  - Shawcross, Hartley and Joan Shawcross, 1953-1954 (Box 68, Folder 23)
  - Sheehan, John J., 1954-1963 (Box 68, Folder 24)
  - Shelton, Robert
  - Shepardson, Whitney, 1953, 1959 (Box 68, Folder 25)
  - Shepherd, Lemuel C., Jr., 1952-1953 (Box 68, Folder 26)
  - Sherbatoff, Mara, 1956 (Box 68, Folder 27)
  - Sherwood, Robert E., 1948-1955 (Box 68, Folder 28)
  - Shibley, Gerald S. and Florence Miller Shibley, 1956, 1961-1966 (Box 68, Folder 29)
  - Shirer, William L., 1945-1946, 1955 (Box 68, Folder 30)
  - Shotwell, James T., 1931-1940, 1954-1965 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Shriver, R. Sargent, Jr., 1966-1967 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Shubert, J. J.
  - Shubert, Lee, 1942 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Shuman, Charles B., 1959 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Shuster, George N.
  - Sibelius, Jean, 1954 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Sillcox, Lewis K., 1945-1965 (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Silver, Abba Hillel, 1958 (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Silver, Charles H., 1956-1958 (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Silverman, Sam, 1939 (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - Simon, Marie-Claire
  - Simons, Dolph, 1951-1967 (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - Simons, John, 1933-1934 (Box 69, Folder 11)
  - Simpson, A. D., 1953, 1959 (Box 69, Folder 12)
  - Simpson, Robert, 1948 (Box 69, Folder 13)
  - Simpson, Wallis Warfield
  - Sinclair, Gregg M., 1946-1963 (Box 69, Folder 14)
  - Sitton, Claude, 1964, 1968 (Box 69, Folder 15)
  - Sitwell, Osbert, 1945, 1948 (Box 69, Folder 16)
  - Skinner, Cornelia Otis, undated (Box 69, Folder 17)
  - Skouras, Spyros P., 1950, 1954 (Box 69, Folder 18)
  - Slade, Alice Patterson
  - Sloane, Kay, 1948-1949 (Box 69, Folder 19)
  - Smalley, Walter B., 1956-1960 (Box 69, Folder 20)
  - Smertenko, Johan J., 1944-1947, 1957 (Box 69, Folder 21)
  - Smidt, Klaas, 1952-1960 (Box 69, Folder 22)
  - Smith, Alfred E., 1931-1938, 1956 (Box 69, Folder 23)
  - Smith, Allan E., 1959 (Box 69, Folder 24)
  - Smith, C. R.
  - Smith, Gerald L. K.
  - Smith, Joseph Kingsbury
  - Smith, Paul C., 1953-1955 (Box 69, Folder 25)
  - Smith, Robert Aura, 1931, 1947-1959 (Box 69, Folder 26)
  - Smith, Walter Bedell, 1947-1950, 1954 (Box 69, Folder 27)
    Includes Walter Waggoner's confidential reports on two off-the-record meetings with Smith, then Under Secretary of State, about international affairs (1954) and correspondence about the NYT's publication of Smith's memoirs as Ambassador to the USSR (1949-1950).